Hi, Mom! I'm home!
What you cook in there? It smells amazing!
It's your birthday, remember?
I made all the recipes you love.
Wow! You made them all?
Every single dish.
See? I whipped up all of your favorites.
Fresh from the bells of the dungeon!
Good morning. You okay?
I had a nightmare.
That's what I smelled in my nightmare!
Can you guys smell that, too?
Yep. The party across the way is making breakfast.
They're having salted pork?
On buns?
It's not fair!
It's horrible.
Breaks my heart to see it.
These days, the diet of young adventurers is a travesty.
They only eat bread, dried meats, and wine.
Look, I get it. Exploring dungeons takes stamina, which you build, by eating fatty meat.
But fat ain't enough.
Malnutrition is the real monster here.
Now that I said my piece, I feel like a total hypocrite, because we have yet to eat a balanced meal.
Elf girl, you know why you were drooling over that salted pork yonder?
It's because your body's craving fat, that's why.
It's because I don't want to eat monster!
Today, we'll hunt monsters that are rich and fat.
Honestly, it'd be nice if we could find one that laid eggs, too.
Eggs are filling, nutritious, the perfect food.
So, if you spot any eggs around, grab them.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
I am.
Just say it.
The body of a chicken.
The tail of a snake.
With spurs, sharp as knives, and loaded with venom.
Basilisk, the king of snakes!
All right, a basilisk.
Isn't that great, Marcel?
You'll get to eat chicken meat.
Is it, though?
Can you call it a chicken when it's half chicken?
Man, what a cool concept.
I always loved monsters that were a mix of more than one species.
Something about mashing two species together elevates the appeal of each one.
The basilisk makes you appreciate the things about a plain old chicken that make it special.
A simple combo, but it really makes you think.
By the way, here's a fact about the cockatrice and basilisk.
Same family, different species.
It's been my dream to do a taste test between the two.
You got some weird dreams.
There should be a basilisk nest here.
There's one.
The eggs look freshly laid, too.
Let's bag them up before the folks come home.
Are they supposed to be that long?
Here, take it.
But are they supposed to be this squishy?
The cry of the basilisk.
Come on, Senshi.
I hope you wrapped yours in something soft like I did.
What's the party with the grill?
Hmm, bad escape technique.
She's just asking to be kicked in the back.
Would you just hurry up and save her?
Spread your arms and legs out wide to look huge.
Then do a crazy yell to sound threatening.
It'll freak the thing out and keep it back.
How about we pretend we don't know him?
Stop!
The basilisk has another head on its tail, so it seems like it has no blind spots.
But it's still one body.
So if you attack both heads at the same time, you'll split its tension in two directions.
Confusing the whole body.
How is he?
Did he get poisoned?
Yes.
Laios!
Senshi says he has an antidote.
Let's have it, then.
Actually, I was planning to use it for lunch today.
Huh?
He's dying!
Can't you see that?
Yeah, well, it's better to take one of these antidotes if it's cooked into something.
Then hurry up and cook something!
First, you gotta chop off the tail and feet.
Parboil it for a sec, then pluck the feathers.
Whoa!
Looks like normal chicken.
Next, you gotta pull out the guts and rub in some spices.
Chop some vegetables up and cram them in with your medicinal herbs.
Then tie up the cut.
Last, jam a stick through the sucker and give it a good slow roasting.
And it's ready.
Hurry up!
Give him some!
It's so juicy and delicious.
Sorry for the wait.
Here, have some, too.
I can't yet!
I should cast a healing spell, too.
Oh, my gosh.
It's like something the dining hall serves.
That probably does taste exactly like chicken meat.
I heard snake meat tastes like chicken, too.
I'm sorry.
I'll cast that healing spell now.
Oops.
Now I'm ready.
That was so good.
It's the first decent meal I've had in the dungeon.
Um, she and I, we've been trying for three months to get past this part of the dungeon.
But the same monsters wipe us out every single time.
So we thought, since you eat monsters, you could tell us how to get stronger so we can, too.
Oh, sure.
Um, first, improve your eating habits.
Second, get enough sleep.
Third, exercise.
Follow these three rules.
And in no time, you will get stronger.
What an amazing group of adventurers.
I want to be like them.
I don't think we're going to make it to the third floor today.
We spent too much time cooking that monster.
They say red dragons wake up once a month to do their hunting.
That means the one we ran into had just woken up.
So it's probably asleep now, because its belly's full.
I'd like to find it before it finishes digesting my sister.
Hey, Marcel, would you please pick up the pace a little?
Yeah, my sister's doomed.
I'm not slowing us down.
See, nothing's broken.
I can walk.
But you're hurt.
We should take a break.
I'm fine, really.
Oh, please.
Acting tough isn't helping one bit.
You'll just end up really hurting yourself, and then you'll be a burden on the party.
We could take the path outside.
It's easier.
Then we'll have to deal with those pesky big bats.
I can take care of big bats with my magic!
No, it's fine.
We could take the secret path.
There's lots of traps, but few monsters.
I have spells that can disarm traps!
Ah, don't bother.
It's faster to let Chilchuk handle them.
Oh.
If we're taking a path with few monsters on it,
we'll need to stock up on as much food as we can carry.
Won't the leftovers from lunch be enough?
That's mostly meat and eggs.
We need some more vegetables, too.
I know of a spot nearby where mandrakes grow.
Oh!
I know all about harvesting mandrakes!
Leave everything to me!
Mandrakes are basic ingredients for magical potions.
And I'm the expert here in magic.
So follow my lead and do exactly what I say.
You can't just pull a mandrake out, because it'll scream.
If you hear it, you'll either go insane or worse.
Die.
If we do this the wrong way, we'll lose time.
And poor Fallon is pretty much doomed.
So here's how we do this.
First, we need one well-trained dog and one leash.
A dog?
Connect the dog to the mandrake with the leash.
Call the dog from a safe distance.
The dog will run to you and pull the mandrake out.
What happens to the dog?
It dies.
That's horrible.
And where are we supposed to get enough dogs to sacrifice?
Wouldn't you say this plan is not only cruel, but totally inefficient?
But that's what I was taught.
Can't we just use a really long piece of rope?
What?
If we used a rope that's long enough so we couldn't hear the scream,
we wouldn't need to kill a dog.
Uh, there's a reason that won't work.
Something about getting the right angle when you pull, or something.
That was scary.
Nice, Marcel.
If you just cut their heads off first, they won't scream.
Makes sense.
But that's not the right way!
I've been doing it this way for years.
But this isn't like picking carrots.
It's really dangerous.
Senshi obviously has experience picking them.
And speaking of, have you ever tried to do this like how your book's telling you?
No, I felt sorry for the dog.
Well, we don't have a dog, and we're wasting time talking about it.
Sorry, but we're doing it Senshi's way.
If such an easy method was safe, it would have been in the book and taught at school.
What was I thinking, trying to get them to believe how the book says to pick a mandrake
when I never tried that way before?
That's right, I haven't.
That settles it.
I'll show them the book's method is the right way.
Then they'll see.
I'm so sorry, boys.
I forgive you.
Now what can I use instead of a dog?
A monster!
This floor is chock full of big bats.
They should all be sleeping in their nests now.
I hope this works.
The book doesn't say how much strength it takes to yank these out.
You know, it's a big bat nest by all the dung.
I never thought Laios' trivia would come in handy.
Now, I need to find somewhere far enough that I can't hear the scream.
Like there!
I can hit it from here easy.
Aere fa'un orbit!
Yes!
Ow! What the heck?
Marcel.
Having experience is important.
For example, now I know using a big bat instead of a dog is a stupid idea.
Marcel!
Is she dead?
Oh, hey there.
You used a big bat instead of a dog, huh?
That's stupid.
Hey, can you hear me?
You okay there?
Yeah, I can never feel better.
Yeah, right.
She heard the scream.
Let's keep talking to her and it'll help clear her head.
Why do you do that?
When I heard my party call me a bird and I freak out.
I do what I did to get back at him and make him grovel out of my foot.
Why, you rotten!
Take it easy.
If I feel like I'm in a way and not helpful, it makes me real sad.
The deeper we get in here, the tougher the monsters.
We need your magic to keep us all safe.
I don't want you wasting your power when we're just three floors down.
We all have strengths and weaknesses.
And when things get crazy, I'm going to need you to be ready.
Till then, we can take care of everything else.
We like to feel useful, too.
Go on, Chillchuck.
Tell her.
I was wrong to say you were a burden.
You've been a big help since day one.
Say it like you mean it, shorty.
I see you've got your lousy attitude back, you little...
This is great.
We snagged ourselves a nice, fat big bat.
How's about we make some omelets?
Are we 100% sure this thing's an egg?
It looks nothing like any egg I've ever seen.
That's what a snake egg looks like.
But only the tail part of it's the snake.
All the chickeny parts are the body.
Uh-uh.
The chickeny part's the tail.
Hmm, this one's a different color than the others.
You're right.
Oh, that's the one Marsil got.
It still has a head.
Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
First, you chop the mandrakes up and stir-fry them for a bit.
Crack an egg and whip it.
Once it gets all fluffy in the pan, it's ready.
Compared to a chicken egg, this is yellowier.
This one's got the mandrake we picked in it.
And this one's got the mandrake, the elf girl, picked using her big bat method.
Sure, keep rubbing it in, why don't you?
Now, now.
Hmm.
The one with Marsil's mandrake is less bitter and more velvety.
It is good.
I guess it loses whatever toxins it has when it screams.
The basic rule of cooking is the more effort you put in, the better the taste.
I was so hell-bent on being efficient, I totally forgot that fact.
My apologies, Marsil.
You and that cookbook of yours were right.
Hey, this is not a cookbook!
As thanks for pointing out my mistake.
I saved the tastiest parts for you.
Oh, no!
I don't want it!
I'm sick and tired of eating these sticky monsters!
The entrance to the secret path should be around here.
I don't see it.
Lyos, can I borrow your sword?
Here it is.
How the heck did he know?
Chilchuk is a specialist in finding traps and picking locks.
All right, people.
There's tons of traps coming up, so don't make a move until I say so.
One thing I hate more than anything is people getting in my way when I'm trying to work.
Hmm.
Stop!
Only step where I just stepped.
What are you doing?
I clearly said only step where I just stepped.
Why is your foot hanging over on this other tile?
I don't nitpick details.
But the details matter.
If you don't watch your step, you'll kill someone.
There are all kinds of traps.
Some of them go off in tandem and some affect each other.
If you trigger one of them, all my calculations go right out the window.
Open your ears and step where I tell you to!
Wait!
Ah!
Hmm.
This room's got all sorts of traps.
This one would crisp you up before you knew it.
Get off that tile already!
Fire traps spray oil and it won't stop till you move your dang foot!
Oil?
The last thing I need is a roasted dwarf!
Roasted, huh?
No, not roasted.
Huh?
Fried.
No, deep fried.
Kakiage!
We're having tempura for lunch today.
You know where the oil for this trap is stored?
It's not used for cooking.
All right, half-foot kid.
You an expert in cooking oil now?
I hate it when people call me kid.
Vegetable oil is the most common, and I bet that's what it is.
Either way, I just want to check it for myself.
If not...
No worries, I won't use it.
All right, fine.
But from now on, when we're dealing with traps, you have to swear you'll do exactly what I tell you!
If you don't like following my orders, you can find the oil yourself!
I swear I'll do what you say, and I'll help if you want.
I don't!
Look, we each have a specialty, don't we?
You cook!
I disarm traps and pick locks!
Marcel Magix!
I'd never tell you how to cook something, ever!
So as a professional courtesy, leave me alone so I can do my job!
I knew it.
This is a treasure room.
All those traps were designed to protect it.
It's bolted down.
I should check inside this one.
Give me some space!
He doesn't have to get all snippy about it.
He knows if he screws up, we're dead.
He's just stressing out about it is all.
It's open.
Great.
So how are we gonna get the oil out of it?
I have no idea.
This looks like the spout, and this is the trigger, and if you pull on it, the oil comes out.
I think.
Okay, I'll hold the pot, and you pull the trigger thingy.
Huh?
That's crazy!
It's filled with boiling oil!
Don't worry.
I'm worried!
You asked for it!
Hot, hot, hot, hot!
That's what I was worried about.
You okay?
Ah!
Your thumb!
Hmm, 180 degrees.
Perfect temperature for deep frying.
So, you didn't feel that at all.
That smell.
That taste.
This here is olive oil.
You're kidding.
There used to be tons of olive trees here, and olive oil's easy enough to make.
Huh, figure someone would use it in a trap.
Yeah, I guess.
Now we can deep fry things.
Oh!
We can use that big blade from the trap in the ceiling to chop the meat.
Hold on!
We don't know if that trap will react the same way!
Since I'm no good at dealing with traps, I'll leave trap stuff to the expert.
Do I really have to do it?
Cooking's my specialty, so you have to do whatever I say now.
Those are the terms we agreed to.
I never agreed to that.
What the hell am I doing?
The big bat's all cut up.
Thanks.
Max, get that fire trap going and heat this oil up.
Go on, you got this.
While he's doing that, I'll strip the skin off the meat, then chop the meat into chunks.
After scoring the meat with a knife, I'll rub in some spices and let it rest.
Now's as good a time as any to prepare the mandrake kakiage.
Before you peel its skin off, you should remove its arms and legs.
If they're all tangled, just separate them and they rip right off.
Scrape all the skin off the body and where the arms and legs were, give those places a scrape, too.
Next comes the batter.
Mix a basilisk egg with water, then sift in a bit of flour,
give it another mix-in and make damn sure there's no clumps,
then add the chopped mandrake.
How's that fire coming?
I have no idea.
It's not like I ever used a fire trap for cooking before.
Oh, it's just about right.
Once it's fried enough, it doesn't fall apart.
Flip it.
Got that?
Yeah, I got it.
Is it ready?
Damn it, it wasn't ready.
Maybe it needs more heat.
I burned it.
How's it coming along?
Horribly.
Can you just do this?
Fire traps are your specialty.
Traps are my specialty, but deep frying's a cooking thing.
If the heat's too low, it's gooey.
With too much heat, it burns right away.
Then it's not your specialty after all.
This batch looks okay.
I like the color of that.
And it's ready.
I never thought eating deep-fried food was possible in a dungeon.
This came out perfect.
The heat was just right.
When you deep fry, you do it quick at a specific temperature.
That's how you get it nice and crispy.
It's hard to get it right doing it over a campfire.
Not that anyone should use a campfire.
I've been on this floor a bunch and never knew about this useful room.
It's dangerous!
Don't ever come in here without me.
Got it?
You'll end up killing yourself.
I hear you.
And for the record, the way you handle traps is amazing.
You sure know your stuff.
The day we go our separate ways will be a sad day for me.
I can't figure traps like you, that's for sure.
It's not all that hard.
When we get some downtime, I guess I can teach you a little about traps.
Really?
This could go bad in so many ways.
But you did teach me a couple of your cooking skills.
Meat cannot replace bread, and bread cannot replace meat.
But combine them, and they can be quite delicious.
So it is with meals and people.
Delicious in Dungeon.